<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>frinj on Martin Trojer</title>
    <link>https://martintrojer.github.io/tags/frinj/</link>
    <description>Recent content in frinj on Martin Trojer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://martintrojer.github.io/tags/frinj/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Frins, a practical unit of measure calculator DSL for Scala</title>
      <link>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2013-06-25-announcing-frins-a-practical-unit-of-measure-calculator-dsl-for-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2013-06-25-announcing-frins-a-practical-unit-of-measure-calculator-dsl-for-scala/</guid>
      <description>I am proud to announce a new Scala project called &amp;ldquo;Frins&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Frins is a practical unit-of-measure calculator DSL for Scala.&#xA;Key features;&#xA;Tracks units of measure through all calculations allowing you to mix units of measure transparently Comes with a huge database of units and conversion factors Inspired by the Frink project Full source code available on github.&#xA;To wet your appetite head straight over to the example calculations.&#xA;How Frins came about About a year ago I created Frinj.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Live Unit Feeds to Frinj</title>
      <link>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2012-03-14-adding-live-unit-feeds-to-frinj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2012-03-14-adding-live-unit-feeds-to-frinj/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks has passed since I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed Frinj to github and blogged/tweeted about it. The response have been pretty awesome, one highlight being when @stuarthalloway showed me a frinj+datomic example gist on the #datomic IRC channel. In short, the Clojure community is #badass.&#xA;Frinj comes with a big database of units and conversion factors, and while as many conversion factors are &amp;ldquo;eternal&amp;rdquo;, others aren&amp;rsquo;t. Exchange rates for instance has to be kept up to date to be relevant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Frinj, a practical unit of measure calculator DSL for Clojure</title>
      <link>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2012-03-03-announcing-frinj-a-practical-unit-of-measure-calculator-dsl-for-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martintrojer.github.io/post/2012-03-03-announcing-frinj-a-practical-unit-of-measure-calculator-dsl-for-clojure/</guid>
      <description>I am proud to announce a new Clojure project called &amp;ldquo;Frinj&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Frinj is a practical unit-of-measure calculator DSL for Clojure.&#xA;Key features;&#xA;Tracks units of measure through all calculations allowing you to mix units of measure transparently Comes with a huge database of units and conversion factors Inspired by the Frink project Tries to combine Frink&amp;rsquo;s fluent calculation style with idiomatic Clojure Full source code available on github.&#xA;To wet your apatite head straight over to the sample calculations page to see what Frinj can do!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
